Amal Joy Chemparathy

Berlin, Germany amaljoyc@gmail.com

LINKS

GitHub

https://github.com/amaljoyc

LinkedIn

https://de.linkedin.com/in/amaljoyc

Personal Blog

https://amaljoyc.github.io/

SKILLS

Expert

Java

Spring Core

Spring Cloud

Maven

Microservices

PostgreSQL

Linux / Bash

Prior Experience

Python

Django

Groovy

Jenkins

Docker

Chef

NodeJS

Kafka

Languages

English (Expert)

German (Basic)

Malayalam (Native)

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer with 7+ years of professional experience in the design, architecture and development of many Software Applications. I have a strong passion for solving problems and building products and solutions through the application of technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018 - present LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER - smava GmbH

- ✓ I'm currently refactoring smava's Legacy Monolithic applications into Scalable Microservices using Spring Boot and Spring Cloud.
- ✓ As a Tech Lead, my responsibilities are to make Tech decisions, Design and Architect various software components and support its Development, manage both Project and Delivery, and hire new Engineers.
- ✓ Reporting to Engineering VP.
- ✓ Tech Stack includes Java 8, Spring Boot, Maven, Microservices, PostgreSQL, Redis (ElastiCache) etc.

2016 – 2018 SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER – smava GmbH

- ✓ Developed the backend logic for smava.de and various other internal projects using Java/Spring/Maven for development and PostgreSQL for data persistence.
- ✓ Developed many Product Solutions for Marketing, CRM, Customer Facing App etc.
- ✓ Worked on very complex and legacy monolithic applications as well as some new micro-services.
- ✓ Hands-on experience building APIs for the frontend, integrating third-party APIs, building Backend For Frontend, Security Management in web apps etc.
- ✓ Did some scripting using Bash, Python, Groovy, and Jenkins for automated deployment and testing.
- ✓ Used Java, Spring, Maven, DataNucleus, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Git, Linux, Bash, Jenkins, NodeJS, Kafka etc.

2015 - 2016 IT CONTRACTOR - Deutsche Telekom AG

- ✓ Lead the development / support of a 4 year old telecom project named HCS-RCS (configuring handsets to use Message+ Application).
- ✓ Worked closely with Product Owner following Agile / Scrum based development.
- ✓ Main support/contact for the Development, QA and Operations team.
- ✓ Used Technologies and Tools like Java 7, Groovy, Spring, Maven, Git, LDAP, Chef, Docker, PostgreSQL, Linux.

2013 - 2015 SYSTEMS ENGINEER - Infosys Ltd.

- ✓ Provided Software Services by performing end to end development like analysis, design and implementation of user stories including unit and integration testing.
- ✓ Implemented SOAP and REST interfaces. Used LDAP and PostgreSQL for data storage. Other tools used were Java 6, Spring, Maven, Git, Linux, Chef.
- ✓ All projects using Agile (Scrum) software development methodology.

2012 - 2013 INTERN PROGRAMMER - Aplopio Technology

- ✓ Involved in the development of the recruiting software Recruiterbox (recruiterbox.com).
- ✓ Worked on server-side / backend web development using Python and Django with PostgreSQL and MongoDB for data persistence.

2010 – 2012 **WEB ADMINISTRATOR / STUDENT INTERN** – Toc H Institute of Science & Technology

✓ Maintained (minor development and bug fix) an internal college departmental website.

EDUCATION

2008 – 2012 Bachelor of Technology
Computer Science & Engineering
Cochin University

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAININGS

2019	Microservices Architectural Design Patterns Playbook Pluralsight Course
2018	Getting Started with Apache Kafka Pluralsight Course
2018	Spring Cloud Fundamentals Pluralsight Course
2015	Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 6 Programmer
2013	Programming Languages Coursera Course Certificate